<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence</title>
    <description>Human mind and its cognition have always been facinating elements the blog tries to give an understanding of it</description>
    <link>http://rikithreddy.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rikithreddy.github.io//zfeed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:50:51 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:50:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>

        <title>The Power of your subconscious mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every person has this intriguing question in his mind on how the human cognition works. I was struck with the same question for most of my life. Recently I came across the book “The power of your subconscious mind” by Dr. Joseph Murphy which gives an amazing outlook on how our brains work. 
&lt;!--more--&gt;
 Dr. Murphy suggests that the human mind is divided into two parts the conscious and the subconscious mind. He portrays them as a ship’s captain and its crew respectively, The conscious mind is the ship’s captain orchestrating all the actions such as ,  reasoning, deduction, and execution of various tasks, on the other hand, the subconscious mind is like the crew of a ship which follows the orders its given its obedient and performs all orders its given to perform the tasks, it doesn’t reason with the orders from the conscious mind and executes them extracting the infinite knowledge gathered through various experiences it had  throughout its life. According to him, we use the conscious mind as a filter to guide what actions can reach the subconscious as it readily accepts any order given and starts executing it with all the infinite intelligence. He shows strong illustrations on how by tapping into the intelligence of the subconscious helped people solve various problems related to many areas such as health, wealth, social problems to even amazing inventions that were possible. This book made me reminiscent of my memories where I realized I  successfully tapped into subconscious mind’s rich intelligence. I would like to share one it which helped me develop complete faith in the infinite intelligence and power the subconscious mind holds, which is just waiting to be unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing chess is one of my hobbies. During my Btech 2nd year our institute held a sports fest where I decided to participate. Most of the competitors were quite proficient who had taken part in many national level competitions, I was intimidated by their rankings and the overwhelming list of achievements they had. However, I decided to challenge myself to take part and being a person who hates losing I made up my mind that if anyone is going to win that would be me. In the league stages, I was placed with other casual players like me where I won flawlessly. Eventually, the matches grew more difficult and intense with each round. As the tournament proceeded the number of audiences grew, Many of the spectators started claiming that my matches were very peculiar, they found something really odd about them, it was the time I took for each of my moves which seemed really fast, even I was bit surprised how I was able to get images of the best possible moves even in most difficult of the situations spontaneously without thinking much, I was literally receiving visuals of the best available move without thinking back then I used say that I was playing moves with my intuition and not my reasoning which was the reason I was able to move so fast. But now I realize after reading Dr. Murphy’s writings what exactly was happening, First I was able to successfully convince my conscious mind that I can win, with faith I was successfully able to tap into the infinite intelligence my subconscious thereafter which was producing these images. What happened later made me realize how the subconscious mind is highly susceptible to our thoughts and why it is important to always stay positive and never get clouded with thoughts like “I can’t”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tournament continued and eventually I was able to reach the finals, however, the person I was going to face was one of the strongest players our institute had. I had never won any of my previous encounters with him, in fact, I was brutally crushed where all the matches were completely one-sided.  I was there intimidated with no hope to win, even before the match started I found saying to myself “its all in vain”, “there is no way I can beat him”, “he has way too much skill”. The match started and as expected he completely dominated the game and taking my Queen piece quite early. I completely lost hope, all odds were against me, I started accepting the reality that I couldn’t win. Luckily, for a while I took my mind off the board, I could see few people who wished I won, their faces all disappointed. I started realizing I didn’t actually try winning, I accepted that I couldn’t win even before I began. Immediately I erased all the negative thoughts I was clouded with. I just had to win, I could win, I just needed to try harder. I filled these thoughts and repeated them. And yes a miracle happened, even though at a great disadvantage I was able to turn the tables as soon as I removed the negative thoughts. The book made me realized that I made a suggestion to my subconscious mind that I couldn’t win which it accepted and thus I wasn’t able to leverage its infinite intelligence, I started losing the game, but as soon as I removed the negative suggestion I had given to it I regained access to the infinite intelligence I held within, leading to a miracle which wouldn’t be possible in normal circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Dr. Murphy says our subconscious mind is susceptible to our thoughts and suggestions it will try its best to make sure they turn into reality, think about chaos and thus shall it follow think about prosperity and success, have faith in it and the subconscious mind makes that possible. The book has been an eye-opener to me on how we can train our subconscious to draw forth the infinite intelligence we hold within. The book demonstrates many methods which can help you train your subconscious.  Its a really great book which can help you prosper in life and I do recommend you try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy the book at: The Power of Your Subconscious mind&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rikithreddy.github.io//cognition/2015/03/31/TestBlog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rikithreddy.github.io//cognition/2015/03/31/TestBlog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Cognition</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
