<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rikith's Blog</title>
    <description>One or more sentences introducing this blog.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 01:06:05 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 01:06:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kiss of Death</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first ever inter-IIIT sports meet was scheduled at IIIT Kanchipuram, during Winter of 2016. We reached there on behalf of our institute - IIITG, unaware of what awaited us. It was an experience we could never forget. We were in high spirits for the games that were scheduled. It was afternoon and we were on our way to the college mess, an attractive structure with glass windows all over the place and an overall great ambiance. However, the weather seemed pretty unusual. There was a fierce wild wind blowing, with increasing speed. We started receiving warnings via phone calls about the forecast of the “Vardah cyclone of 2016”. We got stuck in the mess, unable to get out. The wind, blowing at a speed of 130-150 kms per hour, was strong enough to push people away. The situation worsened when the glass building started to shake and shards of glass started breaking into a million pieces. We were dead scared by all the commotion. We moved to the kitchen, where it was a bit safer but the sound of the wind creeping up on us was terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After couple of hours, we decided to go to the hostel since we were unable to stay there for long. However, the wind was too strong and the campus being still under construction, there were heavy material such as rakes, rods, and other dangerous stuff flying all around. We braved our way through this live warzone to reach the hostel, feeling like the protagonists of a high adrenaline movie or game. Even though I put up a brave face, in reality I was numb with fear. Several of my mates had already reached the hostel by now, making me feel as though I was on my own. Adding to this ill fate, I managed to leave my glasses behind in my room, which gave me a blurry, smoky vision. Cold, shuddered, and abandoned, I literally saw my death in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally a senior student from IIIT Kanchipuram came to me. He shook me hard to bring some sense into me because I was unable to react to the whole forbidding atmosphere. He told me that we needed to leave soon. Pulling me up, we rushed to the hostel, running amidst construction material zooming through the air. We were stuck in between an area where there were quiet a few rakes fluttering around. I was almost about to be hit by a sharp rake, when he pulled me aside saving my life. I cannot put into words, what I felt in gratitude for him, at that moment. I would probably have died that day without him. We rushed through the path immediately and he took me to his room giving me some warm clothes to put on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my friends were searching for me, as they missed my presence. There was no network or any means to communicate or regroup, so I had to stay with the local students. They were kind and warm people and gave me some clothes and food. Later I got in touch with the other students, who happened to be in the same building as me. The cyclone slowly settled down, but what came next was even worse - the after effects of the cyclone. There was no power, no drinking water, no Internet nor any network. It felt like we were stuck in a cave in the old ages. The next two days were hell, as we had to walk almost a mile to get water and our mobiles were uncharged. We had no means to communicate with our parents, to even tell them that we were safe. Even the hostel allocated to us had collapsed and we had to pick our belongings from the debris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, by the grace of God, things got better and the games were finally conducted. Our college secured the third position! We won some prizes and got to stay alive after a direct confrontation with one of the worst storms in the history of our country. Hence, it was a happy ending. In retrospect, this incident had quite an impact on me. Experiencing such a close brush with death gave me a clear picture of how valuable my life is. It taught me to survive through a metaphorical hell and I realized how fortunate I am today, to be living the life that I have. Again, I am really thankful to the student from IIIT Kanchipuram who saved my life, without whom I would not have been able to write about this story of mine today.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 14:30:13 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/archivers/test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/archivers/test</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
